Edwin Dan Lopez Front-end Developer / Web Designer

I help businesses build their presence by developing modern websites and UI

hello@edwindanlopez.com

\(\) 208.794.3982

edwindanlopez.com

github.com/edwindanlopez

Summary

Since my start as a designer working for a creative agency, I have had the opportunity of solidifying my skills in web, graphic, and UI design. As of late, I have been working hard to grow in the field of front-end development to better my skills and understanding of the web. This enables me to continue my career goal of bringing quality experiences and clear communication to the end-user. I would feel privileged with the opportunity to provide my design background and growing knowledge of JavaScript development as a new addition to the team.

Experience

Self-Study - (2021 - Present) (FL)

- ♦ Further education and knowledge in development and programming
- ♦ Kent C. Dodds
 - Epic React workshops (Certificates)
 - Testing JavaScript workshops
- ♦ Egghead:
 - Advanced TypeScript fundamentals, Chrome DevTools Debugging,
 - Next Js, Svelte Js, Tailwind CSS, ChakraUI
- ♦ Books, tutorials, and Readings:
 - ♦ Elequent JavaScript, Auth0, GraphQL, MongoDb, FaunaDB, Groq, SvelteKit

Trading Ally Journaling App - Study project (2021-2022) (FL)

- ♦ Trading Ally is a React application that allows users to log their latest stock trades
- ♦ Incorporate reusable functional components and follow best-practices in passing data between component UI
- Integrate with Fauna DB for data storage
- Integrate Typescript to help increase efficiency in maintainability
- ♦ Future plans include:
 - ♦ Integrating with Netlify ID for user authentication
 - Integrating with the TD Ameritrade API to automatically log trades for users with a ThinkorSwim account

Front-end Developer - BBS Website - Freelance (2021) (FL)

- Provide a consistent yet flexible website solution that allows the business to start small and grow it's online portfolio over time i.e. (Simple layout, category pages, and search tags to expand filtering in the future)
- Provide a combination of libraries and frameworks that will allow for image heavy content without sacrificing speed or user experience (Image optimization, static site generation, and caching)
- ♦ Develop a solution that will allow users to send images or videos of their potential projects for a quote or estimate (3rd party integration)
- ♦ Provide a modern contact form solution with sanitation, validation, and automatic email confirmation response (Library and 3rd party integration)
- Provide on-going website maintenance

Education

2018 University of Central Florida

M.E.R.N. Stack Web **Developer Certificate**

2014 Graduate of Pacific **Union College (BFA)**

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Graphic Design

Skills

Programming Languages

- ♦ Javascript
- ♦ Typescript
- ♦ HTML
- ♦ CSS

Frameworks & Libraries

- ♦ React
- ♦ Gatsby
- ♦ Node JS
- ♦ Svelte

Tools & Platforms

- ♦ Git
- ♦ Vercel
- ♦ Netlify
- ♦ Wordpress
- ♦ Sanity
- ♦ Auth0

Design & Prototype

- ♦ Figma
- ♦ XD
- ♦ Framer
- ♦ Sketch
- ♦ Adobe AI, PS, ID

Experience (Continued)

Senior Web, UI, and Graphic Designer - The DiSTI Corporation (2019-2021) (FL)

- Ideate and restructure website content
- Design and prototype company website for clean developer hand-off
- ♦ Design software product iconography, loading screen, and splash screen
- Create and manage print and digital assets for large trade show events including landing pages, trade show booths, social media and other promotional content
- Design day-to-day marketing collateral such as brochures, info-graphics, banners, posters and press releases

Web Production Management - TT Publications (2018-2019) (FL)

- Lead the design and production of Wordpress websites
- Provide in-house maintenance, support and client training after build
- Provide assistance with logo and marketing designs
- Lead project introduction, set milestones and guide projects through deadlines working with third party vendors and developers

Web & Graphic Design - Freelance (2017-2018) (OR)

- Create branding, marketing assets and provide website development for several clients ranging from a non-profit organization to an emerging musical artist
- Contract with several agencies assisting with website design, email HTML custom template development and marketing collateral design

UI, Web, and Graphic Design - Watson Creative (2015-2017) (OR)

- Design and develop branding strategies, websites, and landing pages along with any other print and digital marketing deliverable
- Prepare mobile and tablet website breakdowns for developer hand-off
- Help train clients use Wordpress CMS
- ♦ Ideate and collaborate in weekly design sprints and critique meetings

Jr. Designer at Fieldtrip Inc. (2014-2015) (OR)

- Ideate and design brand identities, websites, Word booklets and PowerPoint templates along with required marketing graphics
- ♦ Design and develop company RFPs

CF Napa Brand Design Intern (2014) (CA)

- Develop competitive typography sets for packaging and display signage
- Ideate packaging labels, logos, crests and symbol specific to the food and beverage industry
- Design presentation decks for proposals and client meetings
- Mock-up label and packaging designs on different mediums

Traits

- ♦ Thrives in a collaborative environment
- ♦ Focused on sprint objectives
- ♦ Well organized
- ♦ Communicates in a concise manner
- ♦ Possesses a hunger to learn and grow

\(\) 208.794.3982